<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">LHSee</string>
    <string name="menu_start">スタート</string>
    <string name="menu_stop">ストップ</string>
    <string name="menu_pause">一時停止</string>
    <string name="menu_resume">再開</string>
    <string name="menu_easy">簡単</string>
    <string name="menu_medium">普通</string>
    <string name="menu_hard">難しい</string>

    <string name="main_menu_text">LHSee</string>
    <string name="whatIsAtlas_text">ATLASとは</string>
    <string name="threeD_text">ATLAS: 立体表示</string>
    <string name="Vagary_text">ATLAS: 平面表示</string>
    <string name="HiggsHunt_text">ヒッグスを探そう</string>
    <string name="stream_text">イベント: 2次元表示</string>
    <string name="stream3d_text">イベント: 3次元表示</string>
    <string name="stream_3d_text">イベント: 3次元表示</string>
    <string name="gallery_text">イベント 一覧</string>
		<string name="credits_text">作者</string>
		<string name="webview_text">Web リンク</string>


    <string name="reset_zoom_title">ズームをリセット</string>
    <string name="change_view_title">視点の変更</string>
		<!--<string name="test_event">Load test event</string>-->
		<string name="test_event">読込: トップ クォーク イベント</string>
    <string name="unload_event">アンロード</string>
		
		<string name="event0">サンプル 01</string>
		<string name="event1">サンプル 02</string>
		<string name="event2">サンプル 03</string>
		<string name="event3">サンプル 04</string>
		<string name="event4">サンプル 05</string>
		<string name="event5">サンプル 06</string>
		<string name="event6">サンプル 07</string>
		<string name="event7">サンプル 08</string>
		<string name="event8">サンプル 09</string>
		<string name="event9">サンプル 10</string>
		<!--<string name="other_events">Load Example events</string>-->
		<string name="other_events">読込テスト</string>
		<string name="test_event1">イベント 105200_190249</string>
		<string name="test_event2">イベント 106382_27470</string>

		<string name="electron_switch_text">表示/非表示 電子</string>
		<string name="electron_switch_text_a">電子を表示</string>
		<string name="electron_switch_text_b">電子を隠す</string>
		<string name="jet_switch_text">表示/非表示 ジェット</string>
		<string name="jet_switch_text_a">ジェットを表示</string>
		<string name="jet_switch_text_b">ジェットを隠す</string>
		<string name="scalebar_switch_text">表示/非表示 目盛り</string>
		<string name="scalebar_switch_text_a">目盛りを隠す</string>
		<string name="scalebar_switch_text_b">目盛りを表示</string>

		<string name="okay">OK</string>
		<string name="cancel">取消</string>

		<!--<string name="simulation_chat"> The Large Hadron Collider is a 27 km long accelerator. It is underground at the CERN laboratory just outside Geneva, Switzerland. Below you can find a simulation of how the LHC accelerates protons. These tiny particles travel around the 27 km ring, 11 thousand times per second, travelling at 99.999999% of the speed of light. The precision required to make them collide is impressive. Imagine firing knitting needles across the atlantic and getting them to meet. The total energy of the beamis the same as an aircraft carrier travelling at 15 mph. 			
The buttons below will start a simulation of protons.  First they pass through several accelerators, speeding up each time. Then they end up in the LHC itself where they are collide in the center of the ATLAS detector.</string>-->
		<string name="sim_download_warning">動画を再生します. インターネット接続が必要です. </string>
<!--It is recommended to be connected to a wireless network so as not to incur data transfer charges from your mobile network.-->
		<string name="menu_intro">LHSee へようこそ: アトラス実験の全てが分かる! 一番上のボタンを押すと始まります. </string>

	<string name="track_step0">LHC 加速器で陽子の衝突により生成された粒子は、その方向および運動量とエネルギーを測定する検出器をほぼ光速で通過していきます.</string>
	<string name="track_step1">最初に通過するのは衝突点から数 cm 離れた場所に設置されている飛跡検出器です. 電荷を持つ粒子はシリコンの層を通過する際に電子を生成し、それが電気信号として検出されます. デジカメと同様の原理です.</string>
	<string name="track_step2">シリコンの層で電気信号が検出された点を繋げていくと粒子の飛跡 (トラックと呼びます) が分かります.</string>
	<string name="track_step3">ATLAS 検出器は電荷を持つ粒子を曲げるために巨大な二つの超伝導電磁石を備えています. 負の電荷をもつ粒子と正の電荷を持つ粒子はそれぞれ反対方向に曲げられます. 低い運動量を持つ粒子は高い運動量を持つ粒子より大きく曲がります.</string>
	<string name="track_step4">飛跡検出器は衝突点の周りに円筒形に設置されています. 画面の中央で陽子の衝突により生成された粒子が放射状に広がっています.</string>
	<string name="track_step5">青いトラックは粒子の飛跡を示しています. このトラックはコンピューターシミュレーションにより生成されました.</string>
	<string name="track_step6">飛跡検出器を別の角度から見てみます. 画面の左と右からやってきた陽子が中央で衝突します.</string>
	<string name="track_step7">同じトラックを別の角度から見ています. 飛跡検出器は各衝突により生じた粒子の電荷と運動量を精度良く測定します.</string>

	<string name="calo_step0">After passing through the tracking detectors the particles will then continue to the next part of the detector. </string>
	<string name="calo_step1">Calorimeters, outside the inner detector, measure the energy. The inner calorimeter (shown in green) is is most sensitive to photons and electrons. The outer calorimeter beyond is designed for strongly interacting particles (known as "hadrons"). </string>
	<string name="calo_step2">Both calorimeters absorb energy in high-density metal. The energy of the original particle is determined from the sampling measurements. The energy deposited as a function of time could be viewed on an oscilloscope and would look like this. </string>
	<string name="calo_step3">In this wider view, you can see the tracking detectors towards the middle, the electromagnetic calorimeter in green and the hadronic calorimeter in red.</string>
	<string name="calo_step4">Energy deposits in either detector are shown as darker green and red bars in the each section of the detector. </string>
	<string name="calo_step5">The calorimeters can also be seen in a plane parallel to the incoming protons, still enclosing the tracking detector in all directions.</string>
	<string name="calo_step6">You can see the same energy deposits distributed around the detector in this view. </string>
<string name="calo_step7">Electrons and anti-electrons (positrons) have a charged track that point to a large deposit of energy in the electromagnetic calorimeter. Look at the tracks and energy deposits. Can you see any electron candidates?</string>
<string name="calo_step8">The electron candidates are now highlighted in blue.</string>
<string name="calo_step9">Here we can see the tracks and the energy deposits from the electrons in the other view.</string>
<string name="calo_step10">The areas of the detector where the electrons have decayed are now highlighted in blue.</string>
	
	<string name="muon_step0">Zooming out further, we see the enormous (22m diameter) outer tracking system. Its huge size is needed to accurately measure the momentum of muons. Muons are the only charged particles that penetrate the calorimeters.</string>
	<string name="muon_step1">Hits in the muon detectors are combined with those from muons in the inner detector dots producing the total muon track, shown in yellow. Try moving around the detector by touching the screen to follow the path of the muon.</string>
	<string name="muon_step2">Switching views again, we can see the configuration of the muon detectors in a plane parallel to the incoming protons.</string>
	<string name="muon_step3">Again, we can see how the same muon tracks have made there way through the detector in this view. </string>
	
	<string name="met_step0">The final thing that ATLAS would like to measure is the momentum of particles that do not interact with the detector at all. In a collision, the total momentum is the same before and after the collision. This is known as the conservation of momentum.</string>
	<string name="met_step1">The protons colliding at the LHC are at very high energy so many new particles can be produced in each collision. The total momentum of all particles will still be conserved. Here we see a proton travelling away from the screen, that collides with another proton travelling in the opposite direction.</string>
	 
	<string name="met_step2">Sometimes collisions produce particles that are invisible to every part of the ATLAS detector. If we add up the momenta of all particles in the direction perpendicular to the beams we should get zero. A large imbalance indicates an invisible particle has been produced. Here, the trajectory of invisible particle has been added in magenta.</string>
	<string name="met_step3">On the event display, the missing momentum vector is shown in the transverse plane as the magenta arrow. The arrow indicates the direction in which the momentum is missing. The width of the arrow also shows how large the vector is; the fatter it is, larger the missing momentum.</string>

	<string name="events_step0">We are now ready to start identifying kind of events have occured by the particles that have been produced. The first event we can now identify is a W boson decay to an electron and a neutrino. The electron has a track and a deposit in the green electromagnetic calorimeter. The neutrino is invisible so is identified by the missing momentum vector (magenta arrow). Try panning around by scrolling across the screen.</string>
		<string name="events_step1">Here we see the same event but from the side. You can see (in green) the same narrow cone of energy deposited from the electron.</string>
		<string name="events_step2">A W boson can also decay to a muon and a neutrino. This happens at the same rate as it decays to an electron and electron neutrino.</string>
		<string name="events_step3">Again, we can see how the muon travels through the detector</string>
		<string name="events_step4">Another type of event we can now identify is a Z boson decaying to an electron and its anti-particle, a positron. The electron and positron each have a track and an electromagnetic energy deposit (green).</string>
		<string name="events_step5">Here\'s the same event from the side view. Look for the track and electromagnetic energy deposit from each of the two particles</string>
		<string name="events_step6">A Z boson also decays to a pair of muons at the same rate as to an electron / positron pair. Muon tracks are highlighted in yellow.</string>
		<string name="events_step7">Here\'e the same event from the side.</string>
		<string name="events_step8">Our last event has no electrons or muons. Two particles (either quarks or gluons) have each produced two showers of hadrons, which leave energy in both the electromagnetic (green) and hadronic (red) calorimeters. These events are produced at one billion times the rate that W and Z bosons are produced. They are are an unwanted background to all other measurements.</string>
		<string name="events_step9">Here\'s the same background event from the side.</string>

	<string name="animation_intro"> This section will show you what each part of the ATLAS detector is doing and how it is shown in the event display using animations. To go to the previous or next step of an animation, click the left or right arrows on the screen, or the middle button to replay the current step. Click the phone menu button for help.\n
		There are 4 sections that show:\n\n
		<big><b>Tracking</b></big>:\n
		How the paths of charged particles are measured in the middle of the ATLAS detector and how their charge and momentum are calculated.\n\n
		Calorimetry:\n
		How the energy of particles is measured by the calorimeters.\n\n
		Missing momentum:\n
		How the momentum of invisible particles that do not interact with the detector are measured.\n\n
		Muons: How tracks from muon particles are inferred.\n
	</string>
	<string name="animation_intro_title">Animations!</string> 
	<string name="animation_menu_help">Help</string> 
	<string name="help">Help</string> 
	<string name="animation_menu_tracking">Start tracking</string> 
	<string name="animation_menu_calo">Start calorimetry</string> 
	<string name="animation_menu_met">Start invisible particles</string> 
	<string name="animation_menu_muons">Start muons</string> 

	<string name="sixteenth_meter">0.0625m</string> 
	<string name="eighth_meter">0.125m</string> 
	<string name="quarter_meter">0.25m</string> 
	<string name="half_meter">0.5m</string> 
	<string name="meter">1.0m</string> 
	<string name="two_meter">2.0m</string> 
	<string name="four_meter">4.0m</string> 
	<string name="eight_meter">8.0m</string> 

	
	<string name="stream_all">Constant Stream</string> 


		<!--3D button text -->
		<string name="inner_detector_text_a">Show tracking detectors</string>
		<string name="inner_detector_text_b">Hide tracking detectors</string>

		<string name="all_detectors_text_a">Show all detectors</string>
		<string name="all_detectors_text_b">Hide all detectors</string>

		<string name="pixel_text_a">Show Pixels</string>
		<string name="pixel_text_b">Hide Pixels</string>
		
		<string name="sct_text_a">Show SCT</string>
		<string name="sct_text_b">Hide SCT</string>

		<string name="trt_text_a">Show TRT</string>
		<string name="trt_text_b">Hide TRT</string>

		<string name="endcaps_text_a">Show endcaps</string>
		<string name="endcaps_text_b">Hide endcaps</string>

		<string name="calo_text_a">Show Calorimeters</string>
		<string name="calo_text_b">Hide Calorimeters</string>
		
		<string name="muon_text_a">Show Muon</string>
		<string name="muon_text_b">Hide Muon</string>
		
		<string name="split_text_a">Cut detectors in half</string>
		<string name="split_text_b">Re-assemble detectors</string>

		<string name="load_text">Show test Event</string>
		<string name="threeD_help">This Activity shows a completely 3-dimensional representation of the ATLAS detector. By clicking the phone\'s menu button you can choose to show or hide each part of the detector. The detector colours are the same as they are in the 2-dimensional event display, except for the silicon layers which are shown in yellow and white.</string>
		<string name="threeD_stream_help">In this activity, events collected in real time at the ATLAS detector, located at CERN are streamed live to your phone, (provided the detector is currently taking data) and shown in 3D. For options, click the phone\s menu button.</string>
		<string name="threeD_title">Stream ATLAS events in 3D</string>
    <string name="back_to_list_text">Back to List </string>
    <string name="classify_text">Which event is this? </string>
    <string name="loading_text">Loading, please wait </string>


		<string name="event_143">Event 143</string>
		<string name="event_144">Event 144</string>
		<string name="event_166">Event 166</string>
		<string name="event_167">Event 167</string>
		<string name="event_153">Event 153</string>
		<string name="event_156">Event 156</string>
		<string name="event_159">Event 159</string>
		<string name="event_146">Event 146</string>
		<string name="event_157">Event 157</string>
		<string name="event_160">Event 160</string>
		<string name="event_152">Event 152</string>
		<string name="event_232">Event 232</string>
		<string name="event_008">Event 008</string>
		<string name="event_036">Event 036</string>
		<string name="event_052">Event 052</string>
		
		<string name="choose_event_title">Which event do you think this is?</string>

		<string name="Wenu">W -> electron or positron and  neutrino </string>
		<string name="Wmunu">W -> muon or anti-muon and  neutrino </string>
		<string name="HfourL">Higgs boson-> electron-positron and muon anti-muon</string>
		<string name="Zee">Z -> electron and positron </string>
		<string name="Zmumu">Z -> muon and anti-muon </string>
		<string name="dijet"> Dijet background</string>
		<string name="correct"> Correct!</string>
		<string name="incorrect"> Not correct!</string>
		<string name="game_intro"> In this activity you can put your new skills to the test by trying to identify some of the different events that are produced in collisions, using the ATLAS detector. Simply select an event, and if you think you know what it is, choose an event type. There is also a Higgs boson event hidden in here somewhere. As always, click the phone\'s menu button for more options. For more information about the event types, check out the \'What is ATLAS\' section, or visit the website.</string>
		<string name="stream_intro"> In this activity, events collected in real time at the ATLAS detector, located at CERN are streamed live to your phone, (provided the detector is currently taking data). For options, click the phone\s menu button.</string>
		
    <string name="getting_event">Fetching next event</string>
    <string name="no_connection">Please connect your device to the internet and try again.</string>
		<string name="vid_small">Phone (small, 2.5MB)</string>
		<string name="vid_high">Phone (large, 4.5MB)</string>
		<string name="vid_tablet">Tablet (?)</string>
		<string name="game_complete_title">Congratulations!</string>
		<string name="game_complete">You have successfully identified all events in the sample! At the ATLAS experiment, protons bunches collide about 40 million times per second, but only 250 events are written out to disk. Software known as the "trigger" decides whether the event by is interesting and worth recording by deciding what happened in the event, much like what you have just done. For more information about the detectors or the physical significance of these events, please visit our website.</string>
		<string name="menu">Menu</string>
		<string name="anim_finished">You have now completed this section, for more information about the detectors or the types of events, use the main menu to visit the website.</string>
		<string name="anim_finished_title">Section complete</string>
		<string name="event_info">Event info.</string>
		<string name="feedback_text">Feedback</string>
    <string name="feedbacktitle">Enter feedback to send to the developer:\n</string>
    <string
        name="feedbackname">Your Name</string>
    <string
        name="feedbackemail">Your Email</string>
    <string
        name="feedbackbody">Feedback Details...</string>
    <string
        name="feedbackresponse">Would you like an email response?</string>
    <string
        name="feedbackbutton">Send Feedback</string>
    <string
        name="feedbacktype">Enter response:</string>

    <string name="strong_agree">Strongly agree</string>
    <string name="agree">Agree</string>
    <string name="neither_or">Neither agree or disagree</string>
    <string name="disagree">Disagree</string>
    <string name="strong_disagree">Strongly disagree</string>
    <string
        name="feedbacktype4">Bug</string>
    <string
        name="feedbackmessagebody_format">To: The %1$s Department\n\n %2$s\n\n %3$s (%4$s) - %5$s
    </string>
    <string
        name="feedbackmessagebody_responseyes">Requires a response</string>
    <string
        name="feedbackmessagebody_responseno">Does not require a response</string>
    <string name="feedbackmessagesubject_format">Application Feedback </string>
    <string name="enterEmail">Enter Email Address:</string>
    <string name="form_find_out_more">This this app made me want to find out more about Particle Physics and the LHC</string>
    <string name="form_developed_understanding">\nThis app has developed my understanding of Particle Physics and the ATLAS experiment.</string>
    <string name="form_more_study">\nThis app has encouraged me to study Physics at a higher level.</string>
    <string name="form_age">\nI am currently</string>
    <string name="form_background">\nMy level of physics knowledge is:</string>
		<string name="form_lt_15"> less than 15 years old</string>
		<string name="form_15_to_18"> 15 - 18 years old</string>
		<string name="form_over_18"> over 18 years old</string>
		<string name="no_gcse"> None but generally interested / I\'ve watched Brian Cox\'s TV show.</string>
		<string name="gcse"> GCSE / Standard Grade.</string>
		<string name="alevel">A-Level / Advanced Higher.</string>
		<string name="ugrad">Degree level.</string>
		<string name="form_other">\nOther comments.</string>
		<string name="form_dont_alter">*** Please send this email message as it is currently formatted. Thanks! ***\n</string>
		<string name="zoom">Zoom in/out</string>
		<string name="zoom_instructions">To zoom in or out pinch the screen with two fingers.</string>
		<string name="threeD_tour_text">Rotate</string>
		<string name="rotation_text">Rotating</string>

		<string name="vid_connect_error"> The video does not appear to be available for your device. It can also viewed on the ATLAS youtube channel\nhttp://www.youtube.com/user/TheATLASExperiment</string>
		<string name="vid_connect_error_title"> Video Error</string>
		<string name="id_tracks"> inner-detector tracks</string>
		<string name="muon_tracks"> muon or anti-muon tracks </string>
		<string name="ele_or_pos"> electrons or positrons</string>
		<string name="gev_of_met"> GeV of missing transverse energy.</string>


		<string name="simulation_chat"> The Large Hadron Collider is a 27 km long accelerator. It is underground at the CERN laboratory just outside Geneva, Switzerland. Below you can find a simulation of how the LHC accelerates protons. These tiny particles travel around the 27 km ring, 11 thousand times per second, travelling at 99.999999% of the speed of light. The precision required to make them collide is impressive. Imagine firing knitting needles across the atlantic and getting them to meet. The total energy of the beam is the same as an aircraft carrier travelling at 24 kph. 			
The buttons below will start a simulation of protons.  First they pass through several accelerators, speeding up each time. Then they end up in the LHC itself where they are collide in the center of the ATLAS detector. The other two videos are optional extras.</string>
	<string name="get_next_event">Get new event</string> 
  <string name="dl_event_text">Downloading event, please wait </string>
	<string name="silicon_text">silicon </string>
	<string name="straw_text">straws </string>
	<string name="highlight_calos_item">calorimeters </string>
	<string name="highlight_muon">muon chambers </string>
	<string name="coll_occured">Collision time: </string>
		<string name="connTimeout"> Connection timed out. Please try again shortly. </string>
		<string name="colliding_protons">Colliding protons at the LHC.\n\nhttp://www.atlas.ch/multimedia/html-nc/animation-proton-event.html\nThe ATLAS Experiment © 2011 CERN
	 </string>
	 <string name="atlas_assembly">The ATLAS detector assembly.\n\nhttp://www.atlas.ch/multimedia/html-nc/built-in-one-minute.html\nThe ATLAS Experiment © 2011 CERN </string>
	 <string name="higgs_video">The origin of mass.\n\nhttp://www.atlas.ch/contest/\nThe ATLAS Experiment © 2011 CERN </string>
	<string name="animation_pid">Identifying events</string> 
	<string name="trans_proj">X-Y projection</string> 
	<string name="para_proj">R-Z projection</string> 
		<string name="timeout"> Timeout: Please check your connection.</string>
		<string name="TheDefault"> Default </string>
		<string name="highlight_tracking">Tracking detectors. </string>
		<string name="highlight_calos">Calorimeters:\nGreen: Electromagnetic\nRed: Hadronic. </string>
		<string name="highlight_tracking_item">tracking </string>
    <string name="driveLHC_text">Explore the LHC</string>
		<string name="stream_vid">Choose Video</string>
		<string name="need_connection">Choose which video to stream:\n(wifi connection recommended)</string>
		
		<string name="vid_loading">" Video streaming..."</string>



		<string name="topics_interesting">The topics discussed were interesting.</string>
		<string name="phys_level">The level of physics in the app was about right.</string>
		<string name="dev_understanding">This app developed my understanding of Particle Physics and the LHC.</string>
		<string name="encouraged_to_study">This app has helped to encourage me to study Physics at a higher level.</string>
		<string name="dont_know">Don\'t know \/ Not applicable.</string>
		<string name="general_interest">In general, how interested are you in Physics?</string>
		<string name="very_interested">Very interested.</string>
		<string name="fairly_interested">Fairly Interested.</string>
		<string name="not_interested">Not at all interested.</string>
		<string name="age_u11">Under 11.</string>
		<string name="age_11_16">11-16 years old.</string>
		<string name="age_17_18">17-18 years old.</string>
		<string name="age_19_21">19-21 years old.</string>
		<string name="age_22_35">22-35 years old.</string>
		<string name="age_36_50">36-50 years old.</string>
		<string name="age_51_plus">51+ years old.</string>
		<string name="credits_body_text">Content Design: Chris Boddy and Alan Barr\nSoftware: Chris Boddy\n\n\nWe gratefully acknowledge the contributions of our colleagues in the ATLAS collaboration and the ATLAS outreach group and to Ben Waugh and Adam Davidson for sharing their expertise on data visualisation. Consultation and testing from Sam Whitehead, Phil Jones, Dan Short, Alex Pinder and the rest of the Oxford ATLAS group.\n\nInternational Language Support:\nFrench:Hugo Beauchemin\nSwedish: Elias Coniavitis\nGerman: Alex Dafinca\nItalian: Caterina Doglioni\nSpanish: Carlos Escobar\nChinese: Zhijun Liang\nValidation of Spanish and Italian: Mireia Crispin Ortuzar\n\nLogo, Button and consultation from Antartic Design\nhttp://www.antarctic-design.co.uk \n\nFunded by the UK Science and Technology Facilities Council.\nhttp://www.stfc.ac.uk/\nData from the ATLAS Experiment at CERN.\nhttp://atlas.ch/\nwww.cern.ch</string>


		<string name="market_description_text">Want to find out how to Hunt the Higgs Boson using your phone? Ever wondered how the Large Hadron Collider experiments work, and what the collisions look like? 

			Scientists at the world\'s biggest scientific experiment - the Large Hadron Collider at CERN, Geneva - are trying to answer fundamental questions about the nature of the universe, the origin of mass, and structure of space and time.  LHSee makes the Hadron Collider accessible to anybody with an Android smartphone or tablet PC. Written by Oxford University scientists in collaboration with the ATLAS experiment at CERN, it is designed for use by experts and non-experts alike.

			For the first time you can now grab live collision events from the underground detectors in Geneva, and beam them direct to your own device. As well as a variety of educational resources, the application allows you to interact with the collision events in full 3D graphics. You can also find out how the different parts of the detector work, learn how to identify different types of collision, and even put your new skills to the test by playing the "Hunt the Higgs" game.

			Website:
			http://www2.physics.ox.ac.uk/about-us/outreach/public/lhsee 
	</string>
	<string name="market_promo_text"> LHSee: discover what happen at the LHC</string>
	<string name="screenshot_text"> Save Screenshot</string>
	<string name="making_screenshot_text"> Saving Screenshot</string>
	<string name="made_screenshot_text"> Image saved at: </string>
	<string name="noSDcard_text"> Error: could not find SD card. </string>
	<string name="jets_video"> What is a Particle Jet?:\n\nhttp://www.atlas.ch/\nThe ATLAS Experiment © 2011 CERN </string>
	</resources>
